<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Stakeholder participation in agricultural research projects: A conceptual framework for reflection and decision-making</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>A. Neef</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>D. Neubert</dc:creator>
  <DOI xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">10.1007/s10460-010-9272-z</DOI>
  <ISBN-Number xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">0889-048X</ISBN-Number>
  <dc:source>Agriculture and Human Values</dc:source>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:description>&lt;p&gt;Recent discourse in the field of participatory agricultural research has focused on how to blend vari- ous forms and intensities of stakeholder participation with quality agricultural science, moving beyond the simple ‘‘farmer-first’’ ideology of the 1980s and early 1990s. Yet, most existing frameworks of participation in agricultural research still adhere to a linear typology of participatory research with an inherent claim of ‘‘the more participation, the better.’’ In this article, we propose a new framework that looks at participatory research elements along different dimensions and attributes and thus takes into account the diversity and dynamics of agricultural research projects. The framework provides a basis for agricultural researchers engaged in participatory processes with local stakeholders to decide for which issues and in which phases certain participatory elements could be used in a specific research context. Rather than aiming at maximizing the adoption of participatory methods, it can thus become a tool for opti- mizing the use of participatory approaches in agricultural research. We conclude that this framework can be a starting point for a more thoughtful integration of participatory elements in agricultural research projects that does justice to the multidimensional and dynamic nature of stakeholder participation in varying contexts.&lt;/p&gt;</dc:description>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>agricultural research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Framework</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>is research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>learning&amp;facilitation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Participatory approaches</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Scientists</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Stakeholders</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Typologies</dc:subject>
  <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
  <dc:format>179–194</dc:format>
</oai_dc:dc>