<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>FAO Good Learning Pracitices for Effective Capacity Development (Learning module 3)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator />
  <Publisher xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO)</Publisher>
  <URL xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">http://www.fao.org/docs/eims/upload/301361/LM3_Final_en_webready_and_for_CD_9_5_12.pdf</URL>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:description>&lt;p&gt;As Chair of the FAO Interdepartmental Working Group (IDWG) on Capacity Development, it is my pleasure to introduce this Learning Module entitled FAO Good Learning Practices for Effective Capacity Development. This Module is the third title in a series that the IDWG, under the leadership of the FAO Knowledge and Capacity for Development Branch (OEKC), has produced. It reflects the multidisciplinary nature of Capacity Development, which cuts across the entirety of the Organization, and the importance that FAO management and staff have placed upon it. The Corporate Strategy on Capacity Development, endorsed by the Director-General and the member countries, promotes a new mode of action that requires adaptation and change inside FAO. The need for change was reiterated by the Evaluation of FAO’s Activities on Capacity Development in Africa and the FAO Management’s response to it. It is my view that this Module will be useful for FAO Officers and Collaborators involved with developing and/or delivering learning activities in member countries. This Module covers the following curriculum areas: &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Learning activities as modalities for Capacity Development &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Planning and coordinating learning activities &amp;gt;&amp;gt; The Learning Management Cycle &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Evaluation of learning activities &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Selected FAO good training practices &amp;gt;&amp;gt; 8 Toolboxes - on the CD-ROM inside the back-cover The Capacity Development Learning Modules aim to keep FAO staff and consultants abreast of evolving Capacity Development practices in the international development community. I hope you find this Module an effective contribution to your work.&lt;/p&gt;</dc:description>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>capacity building</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>capacity development</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>cd</dc:subject>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:format>272</dc:format>
</oai_dc:dc>