<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/  http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Proceedings of the International Workshop on Agricultural Innovation Systems in Africa ( AISA ),</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>B. Triomphe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>A. Waters-Bayer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>L. Klerkx</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>M. Schut</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>B. Cullen</dc:creator>
  <Publisher xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">AISA Workshop on Agricultural Innovation Systems in Africa</Publisher>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:description>&lt;p&gt;It addresses three main questions of importance when working with agriculture and innovation (particularly in the African context): (i) What insights and lessons can be gained from recent experiences and initiatives to promote and support agricultural innovation involving smallholders throughout Africa?, (ii) How are AIS concepts and approaches being operationalised in Africa? With what successes and challenges? What added value do they bring compared to other approaches to agricultural research and development (ARD)?, and (iii) What are the key implications and recommendations for ways forward in terms of policy, research and practice with regard to supporting agricultural innovation in Africa, and how can these recommendations be implemented concretely in the near future? Specific cases and conclusions leading to better understanding and good practices&lt;/p&gt;</dc:description>
  <dc:language>eng</dc:language>
  <dc:subject>ad&amp;case africa</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>capacity building and development</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>innovation system</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>is actor extension</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>is actor farmer organization</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>is actor ngo</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>is actor research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>is asia</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>is learning and knowledge</dc:subject>
  <dc:type>Conference Paper</dc:type>
  <dc:format />
</oai_dc:dc>