<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ags:resources
  SYSTEM "http://purl.org/agmes/agrisap/dtd/">
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/"
               xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
               xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2"
               xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="UA2015600001">
      <dc:title>Research that matters: outcome mapping for linking knowledge to poverty-reduction actions<dcterms:alternative>Development in Practice</dcterms:alternative>
      </dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Nyangaga, Julius</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Smutylo, Terry</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Romney, Dannie</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kristjanson, Patti</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2010</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>An 'Outcome Mapping' approach was applied retrospectively to five diverse, highly collaborative research projects aimed at poverty reduction. Designed to help plan for, clarify, and document intended and actual changes in behaviour, actions, and relationships of groups and organisations that directly influence a project's intended beneficiaries, Outcome Mapping enabled us to identify and describe the strategies and actions that played important roles in the innovations achieved. Successful strategies observed included the use of champions, jointly producing high-profile outputs that enhanced the status of local partners, multiple communication strategies, targeting ongoing policy processes, and strong emphases on and investment in capacity building. Une approche fondée sur la « cartographie des résultats » a été appliquée rétrospectivement à cinq projets de recherche très collaboratifs et divers visant à réduire la pauvreté. Conçue pour faciliter la planification, la clarification et la documentation des changements prévus et réels sur les plans du comportement, des actions et des relations des groupes et des organisations qui influent directement sur les bénéficiaires prévus d'un projet, la cartographie des résultats nous a permis d'identifier et de décrire les stratégies et les actions qui ont joué des rôles importants dans les innovations obtenues. Parmi les stratégies efficaces observées on peut citer l'utilisation de champions, la réalisation conjointe de produits très médiatisés qui ont renforcé la position des partenaires locaux, des stratégies de communication multiples, le ciblage des processus d'orientation en cours et l'accent mis sur le renforcement des capacités et l'investissement dans ce dernier. Uma abordagem de 'Mapeamento de Resultado' foi aplicada retrospectivamente em cinco projetos de pesquisa diversificados e altamente colaborativos destinados à redução da pobreza. Destinado a ajudar a planejar, esclarecer e documentar mudanças pretendidas e mudanças reais de comportamento, de ações e de relacionamentos de grupos e organizações que influenciam diretamente os beneficiários pretendidos de um projeto, o Mapeamento de Resultado permitiu-nos identificar e descrever as estratégias e ações que desempenharam papéis importantes nas inovações alcançadas. Entre as estratégias bem-sucedidas que foram observadas estão o uso de defensores da estratégia, produzindo conjuntamente resultados de alto nível que melhoraram o status dos parceiros locais, múltiplas estratégias de comunicação, tendo como meta os processos de políticas em andamento e forte ênfase em capacitação. Se aplicó retroactivamente el método de 'mapeo por resultados' a cinco proyectos de investigación que buscaban abatir la pobreza con un alto grado de participación. El Mapeo por Resultados fue diseñado para apoyar la planeación, la depuración y la documentación de cambios intencionados o reales en el comportamiento, las acciones y las relaciones de grupos y organizaciones que afectan a los beneficiarios directos de un proyecto. El Mapeo también permitió la identificación y la descripción de las estrategias y acciones más importantes para lograr innovaciones. Entre las estrategias exitosas que se observaron están la participación de personas célebres, la elaboración conjunta de productos de alto perfil que elevan el prestigio de las contrapartes locales, y distintas estrategias de comunicación, las cuales se centran en lograr cambios en el proceso habitual de toma de decisiones políticas, haciendo énfasis en invertir en el fortalecimiento de capacidades.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">internal-pdf://Nyangaga et al. - 2010 - Research that matters outcome mapping for linking knowledge to poverty-reduction actions.pdf</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">10.1080/09614524.2010.513725</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type scheme="dcterms:DCMIType">Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 972-984</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Development in Practice</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">10.1080/09614524.2010.513725</ags:citationIdentifier>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.20(8)</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>
