<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ags:resources
  SYSTEM "http://purl.org/agmes/agrisap/dtd/">
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/"
               xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
               xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2"
               xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="UA2015600001">
      <dc:title>Integrated Agricultural Research for Development</dc:title>
      <dc:subject>agricultural research</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>innovation systems</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>is research</dc:subject>
      <dc:creator>Hawkins, R</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Heemskerk, W</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Booth, R</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Daane, J</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Maatman, A</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Adekunle, a a</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Africa, Forum for Agricultural Research in</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2009</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>This paper is intended to contribute towards an understanding of ‘Integrated Agricultural Research for Development’ (IAR4D). We first review four ‘defining principles’ of IAR4D, the theories and experiences that have contributed to the formulation of these principles, and actions that can contribute to putting these principles into practice. We then summarize the individual, organizational and institutional capacity that is needed to create the enabling environment for IAR4D. Finally, we look at 13 case studies, and review how they reflect the principles and capacity-development challenges described. The ‘defining principles’ of IAR4D we propose are: 1. IAR4D integrates the perspectives, knowledge and actions of different stakeholders around a common theme. The theme or ‘entry point’ represents a research and development ‘challenge’, identified by one or more stakeholders who recognize that a broader working alliance is needed to achieve the desired development impact. The interests and actions of the different stakeholders go beyond information and technology to include business, politics, finance, organization, management, etc., and the links between these. 2. IAR4D integrates the learning that stakeholders achieve through working together. Beyond simply a concerted action process, IAR4D is a social learning process, with stakeholders learning from the experience of working together. This learning focuses primarily on the processes of stakeholder interaction themselves, rather than on the specific solutions to the research and development ‘challenge’. This learning takes place at the individual, organizational and institutional levels. 3. IAR4D integrates analysis, action and change across the different (environmental, social, economic) ‘dimensions’ of development. The general and current concepts of ‘sustainable development’ and ‘multi-functional agriculture’ emphasize the interlinked ‘dimensions’ of such development. These include economic growth (linking farmers to markets), conservation of natural resources (soil fertility, biodiversity, limited carbon-dioxide production, etc.), social inclusion and equity (‘pro-poor development’), as well as food security. 4. IAR4D integrates analysis, action and change at different levels of spatial, economic and social organization. Agricultural innovation is an emergent property of the broader ‘innovation system’. To be effective at promoting innovation, IAR4D therefore needs to promote change and enhance learning throughout the broad innovation system at all levels of organization. These include ‘spatial’ levels (field, farm, watershed, etc.), economic levels (product, firm, value chain, business cluster, etc.), and social levels (individual, group, community, organization, innovation system, etc.)</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">internal-pdf://Hawkins et al. - 2009 - Integrated Agricultural Research for Development.pdf</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type scheme="dcterms:DCMIType">Unpublished Work</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 96</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <ags:citation/>
   </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>
