<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ags:resources
  SYSTEM "http://purl.org/agmes/agrisap/dtd/">
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/"
               xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
               xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2"
               xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="UA2015600001">
      <dc:title>Putting heads together: Agricultural innovation platforms in practice</dc:title>
      <dc:subject>ad&amp;case africa</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>cd tools</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>innovation platforms</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>innovation systems</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>is multi-stake holders interactions</dc:subject>
      <dc:creator>Nederlof, Suzanne</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Wongtschowsi, Mariana</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>Royal Tropical Institute (KIT)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2011</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>The book documents a diversity of approaches for and results from the development of innovation processes (endorsing the definition proposed by FARA) through a review of twelve agricultural platforms in sub-Saharan Africa. These cases are far from exhaustive but nevertheless bring up a wealth of experiences. The authors do not pretend to present a model or template for the perfect innovation platform. To the contrary – they do not believe this is possible. As such, the objective of this document is not to judge or evaluate the actions and performances of those involved in the implementation of platforms, but to serve as a basis for discussion and learning about this significant and useful development in agriculture. Particularly relevant are the findings about the factors (three) that frequently lead to the disintegration of established innovation platforms: lack of funding, irreconcilable conflicts between partners, and unfavourable changes in the institutional and political</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">internal-pdf://Nederlof, Wongtschowsi - 2011 - Putting heads together Agricultural innovation platforms in practice.pdf</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type scheme="dcterms:DCMIType">Book</dc:type>
      <ags:citation/>
   </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>
