<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ags:resources
  SYSTEM "http://purl.org/agmes/agrisap/dtd/">
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/"
               xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
               xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2"
               xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="UA2015600001">
      <dc:title>Learning for capacity development: a holistic approach to sustained organisational change<dcterms:alternative>Development in Practice</dcterms:alternative>
      </dc:title>
      <dc:subject>cd</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>cd organizational</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>knowled and learning</dc:subject>
      <dc:creator>Thol, Phum</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Chankiriroth, Sim</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Barbian, Dennis</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Storer, Graeme</dc:creator>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
      <dc:subject>development</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>establishing a learning culture</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>forums</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>holistic approach to organisational</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>learning</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>organisational readiness and resilience</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>partnership agreements</dc:subject>
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>This article describes a holistic approach to organisational development that promotes learning and its integration into everyday work practice. It presents the approach and how it leads to genuine organisational transformation, increased organisational efficiency, and resilience during change. When an organisation is both willing and able to engage with a holistic approach, the results are significantly better than any that external one-off interventions or standalone training programmes can produce.\n\nApprendre pour le développement des capacités : une approche globale du changement organisationnel soutenu\n\nCet article décrit une approche globale du développement organisationnel qui favorise l'apprentissage et son intégration dans les pratiques quotidiennes du travail. Il présente l'approche et la manière dont elle mène à une transformation organisationnelle véritable, à une efficacité organisationnelle accrue et à la résilience durant les périodes de changement. Lorsqu'une organisation est à la fois en mesure d'adhérer à une approche globale et disposée à le faire, les résultats sont largement meilleurs que ceux que peuvent produire les interventions exceptionnelles externes ou les programmes de formation autonomes.\n\nAprendizado para o desenvolvimento de capacidades: uma abordagem holística para a mudança organizacional sustentável\n\nEste artigo descreve uma abordagem holística para o desenvolvimento organizacional que promove o aprendizado e sua integração em práticas de trabalho cotidianas. Ele apresenta a abordagem e como ela leva a uma transformação organizacional genuína, maior eficiência organizacional e resiliência durante a mudança. Quando uma organização deseja e é capaz de engajar-se em uma abordagem holística, os resultados são significativamente melhores do que os obtidos por intervenções externas únicas ou programas de treinamento isolados.\n\nAprender a desarrollar capacidades: un método integral para el cambio organizacional sostenible\n\nEste ensayo describe un método integral para el desarrollo organizacional que promueve el aprendizaje y su incorporación a las prácticas laborales cotidianas. Presenta el método y explica cómo su uso puede desembocar en una transformación organizacional genuina, una mayor eficiencia organizacional y una mejor adaptación a los cambios. Cuando en una organización se dan las condiciones y la voluntad para abordar un método integral, los resultados superan ampliamente a los que se obtienen con intervenciones puntuales o con programas de formación aislados.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">internal-pdf://Thol et al. - 2012 - Learning for capacity development a holistic approach to sustained organisational change.pdf</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type scheme="dcterms:DCMIType">Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 909-920</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Development in Practice</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">10.1080/09614524.2012.696581</ags:citationIdentifier>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.22(7)</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>
