<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ags:resources
  SYSTEM "http://purl.org/agmes/agrisap/dtd/">
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/"
               xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
               xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2"
               xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="UA2015600001">
      <dc:title>Evaluating Capacity Development in Planning, Monitoring, and Evaluation</dc:title>
      <dc:subject>m&amp;e</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>m&amp;e impact study</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>m&amp;e tools</dc:subject>
      <dc:creator>Horton, D</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Mackay, R</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Andersen, A</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Dupleich, L</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>International Service for National Agricultural Research (ISNAR)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2000</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>Capacity development has moved to center stage on the agendas of development organizations. As tech- nologies and institutions are changing fast and budgets for overseas development assistance are declin- ing, strengthening the capabilities of individuals, organizations, and institutions is essential to ensure that development efforts are sustainable and poverty is eradicated. Substantial sums are being invested in the development of organizational and institutional capacities. Yet, the design and management of capacity development efforts leaves much to be desired. Few capacity development programs have been systematically and thoroughly evaluated to test their underlying theories and assumptions, document their results, and draw lessons for improving future programs. This report describes the concepts and methods used to evaluate a regional capacity development project in Latin America. The project under study aims to strengthen planning, monitoring, and evaluation (PM&amp;E) in agricultural research organi- zations in the region. The report outlines the procedures employed in five evaluation studies and sum- marizes the results of each study. It then presents consolidated findings in response to three evaluation questions: What were the main contributions of the project to agricultural research management? What lessons can be learned to improve the design of future capacity development programs? What lessons can be learned to improve future evaluations of capacity development?</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">internal-pdf://Horton et al. - 2000 - Evaluating Capacity Development in Planning, Monitoring, and Evaluation.pdf</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">9291180513</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type scheme="dcterms:DCMIType">Book</dc:type>
      <ags:citation/>
   </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>
